Guide to the Frederick Schult Papers MC.207
New York University Archives
Frederick Schult Papers
1926-1997
New York University Archives
Schult, Frederick
MC.207
1 Linear Feet
This collection contains various records collected by Frederick Schult. It includes materials relating to Phi Beta Kappa, such as bulletins and meeting notes, as well as papers dealing with the History Department and the Graduate School of Arts and Science at New York University. Other topics include the Liberal Education Program (LEP).
Arrangement
Folders are arranged in no discernable order.
The files are grouped into one series.
Scope and Content Note
The materials in the collection reflect the diverse experiences and interests of the collector. The majority of the documents date from the late 1980s and the early 1990s. The majority of documents are meeting minutes and administrative reports. Some photographs are included.
Biography of Frederick Schult
Frederick C. Schult was born on June 11, 1928, and attended Stuyvesant High School from 1943 to 1946. He received his B.A. from New York University's College of Arts and Sciences in 1950, and his M.A. and Ph.D. in history from the Graduate School of Arts and Science in 1951 and 1962 respectively. He joined the University faculty in 1951 as an assistant instructor in history at the School of Commerce, and from 1956 to 1962 he served as an instructor of history at the University College of Arts and Sciences. From 1962 to 1969, he served as assistant professor of history, and in 1969, he was named associate professor of history.
Schult also held administrative positions within the University. At the University College of Arts and Science, he served as assistant to the Dean from 1957-1962 and as Assistant Dean from 1962-1970. He also served as a freshman class advisor from 1957-1965 and as the Director of Counseling and Registration from 1965-1970. Additionally, Schult served as an Associate Dean in the Graduate School of Arts and Science.
Schult served in the United States Army from 1954-1956. He is a member of Phi Beta Kappa and Zeta Psi, as well as several historical and educational societies, including the American Historical Association and the Organization of American Historians. He has participated in several University committees, including those devoted to financial aid, student affairs, and academics.
His main academic focus is 19th-century American history.
Access Restrictions
Administrative papers are closed for 20 years following the date of creation. Student information may be subject to FERPA guidelines. Please contact the University Archivist with questions regarding specific materials.
New York (N.Y.).; Universities and Colleges -- Administration; Universities and Colleges -- Faculty.; Correspondence.; Photographs.; New York University. Faculty of Arts and Science; Phi Beta Kappa; New York University -- Administration
- Series I
  - Frontiersman of Fortune: Moses M. Strong of Mineral Point by Kenneth Duckett, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    General note
    bar code #: 3 1142 04227157 0
  - The Presidents of the Beta of New York: A Centennial Memoir by Theodore F. Jones and Richard D. Mallery, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Phi Beta Kappa Bulletin 33rd Triennial Council Meeting, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Phi Beta Kappa Bulletin 34th Triennial Council Meeting, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Phi Beta Kappa Bulletin 35th Triennial Council Meeting, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Phi Beta Kappa Bulletin 36th Triennial Council Meeting, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Phi Beta Kappa Bulletin 37th Triennial Council Meeting, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Phi Beta Kappa Bulletin 38th Triennial Council Meeting, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Memorial Tributes (Various), 1985, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Bayrd Still Memorial, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Journal Articles, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - GSAS Constitutions, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - GSAS Alumni Association Constitution, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Heights Green Groom Society Playbills, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Report on History Program, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence between Dean Musser and Henry Steel Commager [photocopies], 1926 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - History Department Alumni Committee, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Phi Beta Kappa, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - History Alumni Association, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - FAS: LEP [Liberal Education Program], 1980 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - LEP, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - LEP Workshop, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Miscellaneous Documents, undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Photograph of Dean Emeritus Joseph H. Park, undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Series II: Unprocessed Materials (Box 2, Box 3, Box 4, Box 5, Box 6, Box 7, Box 8, Box 9, Box 10)